conservative.ca 2019-12-13

# Privacy Policy - Canada's Official Opposition

### **Our Commitment to Protecting Your Privacy**

Your privacy is important to us. The Conservative Party will respect your privacy through the protection of any of your personal information that you provide to us. We take great care to keep both confidential and secure all personal information in our possession.

As a federal political party registered under the Canada Elections Act, the Conservative Party including its electoral district associations (“riding associations”), candidates, nomination contestants and leadership contestants are subject to extensive regulation under that Act, including in particular public disclosure requirements for contributions over $200.

### **What is “Personal Information”**

“Personal Information” is information about an identifiable individual. It includes information such as name, address, e-mail address, telephone number and other contact information.

### **Collecting Personal Information**

Elections Canada provides all political parties with a list of electors, including names and postal addresses. We collect other information from publicly available data.

We collect personal information from donors and members when they contribute to our Party or purchase a membership. You may also choose to provide us with personal information on a voluntary basis, such as when registering for an event or signing a petition. We are required by law to keep records of donors for tax purposes.

If you submit your e-mail address and/or personal information through our website, you consent to being added to our e-mail list. You may unsubscribe from our e-mail list at any time using the link provided in each email message, or by [clicking here](http://www.conservative.ca/unsubscribe-me/).

### **Usage of Personal Information**

We use your personal information to communicate with you. As a political party, we believe it is important to communicate with Canadians on a regular basis.

As a national organization with a riding-based membership system, your personal information may also be disclosed to our local riding associations, candidates, nomination contestants and leadership contestants who may also communicate with you.

Additionally, non-personal information may be collected by the Conservative Party through the use of cookies, including third-party cookies. Cookies allow us to track how people are using our site and help us deliver better content to our visitors. We may use this information, in aggregate, to improve our site or to assist in advertising.

Visitors can opt-out of many of the advertising features used by this site and others by adjusting their Google Ads Settings, or through free services like the Network Advertising Initiative’s Consumer Opt-Out page: http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/.

### **Protecting your Personal Information**

We maintain security systems to safeguard your personal information from unauthorized access, disclosure or misuse, and from loss or unauthorized alteration.

Employees of the Conservative Party of Canada are trained on the appropriate use of personal information. This training emphasizes appropriate collection, maintenance and use of personal data.

We will not sell your personal information that you have chosen to provide us.

### **Accuracy of Personal Information**

We always try to keep your personal information accurate and up-to-date. If you wish to update your personal information, contact us by e-mail at servicedesk@conservative.ca.

### **External Links**

Our web site contains links to a limited number of other web sites. The Conservative Party is not responsible for the content of these web sites.

### **How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions, concerns, or complaints about the Conservative Party privacy policy or the information we collect, please contact our privacy officer by e-mail at privacy@conservative.ca, or by regular mail at:

Attn: Trevor Bailey, Privacy Officer  
Conservative Party of Canada  
1720 – 130 Albert St.  
Ottawa, ON K1P 5G4

If you no longer wish to receive phone calls or mail from the Conservative Party, you may contact us at servicedesk@conservative.ca. Please include your name, address and phone number so we can accurately deal with your request.
